Piotr Malicki

Machine Learning Developer

Email piotr.malicki92@gmail.com

Address Wojciechowskiego 40 m.59 Warszawa

Website https://nsvdeveloper.netlify.app

Phone 790506500

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/mpiotr



Piotr has been associated with the Data Science and Machine Learning industry for over 6 years, and during his career he has completed many commercial projects for international clients. Currently, he is a Senior Machine Learning Developer and runs freelance projects on the basis of Quantitative Finance in the technology stack: R, Python. In his spare time, he is passionate about off-road driving, especially long expeditions to the Balkans.

Work History

2021-05 - present

Co-Founder | Data Science & Machine Learning Maintainer

Devs-Mentoring

I am experienced trainer in the following subjects:

- statistics
- econometrics
- machine learning
- deep learning
- natural language process
- artificial intelligence applications

I work in the R and Python programming language.

I am also the maintainer and trainer of the Data Science Mentoring Path organized by Devs-Mentoring. I manage the whole teaching process and conduct classes on various topics since 2021.

2021-03 - present

Senior Machine Learning

Best S.A.

Rebuilding business models in Python using mlflow and H2O:

- classification models related to the repayment of the debt collection process
- implementing scikit-learn machine learning pipelines with CI/CD

Working in Natural Language Processing (NLP) domain with Python. Responsibilities:

- developing advanced machine learning and deep learning algorithms
- implementing machine learning pipelines in text mining
- search engine based on deep learning (using siamese networks)
- text classification (multilabel classification)

2020-12 - present

Ceo/Founder

Non Sense Vision

"Artificial Intelligence, deep learning, machine learning — whatever you're doing if you don't understand it — learn it. Because otherwise you're going to be a dinosaur within 3 years."

Mark Cuban

Our mission is to help companies build an efficient, reliable, and performant data platform and organizations using our skills and experience.

2020-12 - present

Data Scientist

Plenti

Implementation of projects related to the innovation voucher for technologies working as R Software Developer. Design and construction analytical dashboard for each department in the company using R, Shiny, Python and Spark, Google Cloud Platform.

2020-09 - 2020-12

Specialist at Credit Risk Department

Raiffeisen Bank International AG

Analysis of business processes and integration of the collective database between systems and collection of requirements for modeling new databases for LGD models in R and Python. Cooperation with the substantive departments in the scope of defining reporting requirements and the subsequent construction of monitoring in the dashboard using R and Shiny.

2020-02 - 2020-08

Chief Risk Management Specialist

Bank Peako S.A.

Generating recurring reports using Oracle Database, SAS and Python. Supporting the development of automation in the area of calculating the capital requirement in R and creating reports with dashboards in Shiny. Implementation of projects enabling the implementation of the new system calculation of the capital requirement. Implementation of the Scrum methodology to the team and creating diagrams in Jira and Confluence along with the subsequent administration of process data.

2019-03 - 2020-01

Data Science Specialist

PKO Bank Polski

Work on the largest data sets in the Polish banking sector (Big Data). Quality monitoring of application models in production using SAS and R in Shiny. Analysis anomalies related to the monitoring of application models. Automatic reporting monitored portfolios in SAS and Python.

2018-11 - 2019-01

Data Science Assistant

Publicis Media

Automation of data preparation, data scraping and API data retrieval with R and Python. Create new analysis work files and data processing along with process automation. Support for existing desktops in Shiny as well creating new ones with Tableau and Power BI.

2016-01 - present

Data Scientist / Statistical Programmer

Freelancer

Work for research and commercial teams focused on R&D industries. Implementation of statistical models, machine learning and deep learning related to time series streaming data, survey data and panel data in R and Python. Working as R Software Developer, building and managing backend and frontend of applications developed in Shiny with support for previously built applications models. Implementation of econometric analyzes in STATA, SPSS and Statistica. Projects:

- 1) Real estate appraisal based on spatial hedonic models. (R, Shiny)
- 2) A bot for the cryptocurrency market based on a scalping strategy. (R, Rccp, Shiny)
- 3) An application for implementing a Forex market strategy based on data streaming. (C++, R, Shiny)
- 4) Dashboard of climate change impacts on real estate prices in London. (R, Shiny)
- 5) Analytical system for optimizing the investment portfolio in the Forex market. (C++, R, Shiny)
- 6) Mutation analysis of fetal cancer genes. (STATA, SPSS, R, Shiny)
- 7) Spatial analysis of the location of cadastral plots for developers (R, Shiny)
- 8) Analysis of the production line, along with the optimization of the demand for new devices (R, Shiny)
- 9) Analysis of application network logs related to international shipping (Python, Dash)
- 10) Others: applications, dashboards and analyzes for the financial industry, pharmacy and the market real estate.

Education

2021-02 - present

Kozminski University

Postgraduate studies, Data Science & Big Data Managment

Thesis: "Credit scoring platform in terms of cloud computing versus classic"

2019-10 - 2020-10

Warsaw School of Economics

Postgraduate Diploma, Academy of Analytics with SAS, R & Python

Thesis I: "Credit Risk Assessment of local government units in terms of dependence spatial"

R package: spcredit

Thesis II: "Arbitrage system on a cryptocurrency exchange"

2018-10 - 2021-02

University of Warsaw

Postgraduate Diploma, Data Science in Business Applications. Workshops using the R programing language

Thesis: "Analysis of scalping strategies on the stock exchange cryptocurrencies" R package: scalpingR

2018-10 - 2021-02

University of Warsaw

Postgraduate Diploma, Economic Data Analysis in Excel and VBA

Thesis I: "Interest analysis of crypto in currencies using Google Trends"

Excel App: cryptoApp

Thesis II: "Analysis toolpack R+Excel+VBA"

R + VBA packages: vbaR

2016-10 - 2022-02

University of Warsaw

Master's degree, Computer Science and Econometrics

Thesis (MSc):"Stopploss analysis in forex and cryptocurrency diversified investment portfolio" R packages: stoplossR

2015-10 - 2022-02 **University of Warsaw** Master's degree, Faculty of Economic Sciences Thesis (MSc): "Analysing spatial patterns between Airbnb and hotel room rental and real estate transactions" R packages: hedonicR 2011-10 - 2014-07 Warsaw University of Technology Bachelor's degree, Faculty of Economic Sciences Specialty: Business Economics Undergraduate dissertation (BSc): "Modeling and forecasting of liquid fuel prices on the Polish market"

Courses

2021-05 **Master R for Data Science** LinkedIn. AUqGiz5VR27rasZfo6K_OXtEL6zo 2021-05 Advance Your Skills as an R Expert LinkedIn . AS3rhNA_qBNxA7qD69SqDPAVz9jd 2021-03 Advanced Credit Risk Modeling for Basel/IFRS 9 using R/Python/SAS BlueCourses 4c135e0c0cd744dda1679fdef67ffce0 2021-03 Basic Credit Risk Modeling for Basel/IFRS 9 using R/Python/SAS **BlueCourses** fdaa7393d1d44f24b1528c70cd188597 2020-01 **Python For Trading MCX** 67252-28-1 2020-12 **R Programming Track** Data Camp #192,279 2020-09 **Bootcamp Python Developer (320h)** Kodilla 10734/2020 2020-09 **Bootcamp Java Developer (720h)** Kodilla 10359/2020 2018-09

Bootcamp Data Science in Python (840h)

Technology Stack

Sages 10734/2020

R	****
Shiny	****
Python	****
Django	****
Flask	****
Dash	****
Java	****

	C++	****
	Oracle SQL	****
	Stata	****
	SPSS	****
	Power BI	****
	Tableau	****
Skills		
	Econometrics	****
	Machine Learning	****
	Deep Learning	****
	Natural Language Processing	****
	Computer Vision	****
Languages		
	English language	****
B2		
	Russian language	****
B1		
Hobby		

Robotics, Raspberry Pi, Blockchain, Microeconomics and Macroeconomics Automotive, Ballroom Dancing